<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Exuberant Sketches</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Exuberant Sketches</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Will Larson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sketches.lethain.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Elegant Puzzle: Systems of Engineering Management</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/elegant-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/elegant-puzzle/</guid><description>An Elegant Puzzle was my first book, published May, 2019. It&amp;rsquo;s available exclusively via Amazon, and was published by Stripe Press.
An overview of the project is available here, and a number of additional posts are available on my blog under the elegant-puzzle tag.
Sales Periodically updated sales tracker.
Format October, 2019 January, 2021 Kindle Digital 4500 450 Hardcover 6000 710 Audiobook 1,500 234 total 12,780 33,493 Note that while all of the total numberes are accurate, but some of the format breakdown are estimates due to the reporting I have available.</description></item><item><title>Staff Engineer: Leadership beyond the management track</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/staff-engineer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/staff-engineer/</guid><description>Learn more about Staff Engineer on staffeng.com.
Sales Periodically updated sales tracker.
Format 2021/2/13 Kindle Digital 700 Paperback 773 Gumroad: Personal (1x) 800 Gumroad: Team (15x) 20 Gumroad: Company (100x) 5 total 3,073</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Engineering Book</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/infra-eng-book/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/infra-eng-book/</guid><description>How to operate and scale technical infrastructure and the infrastructure organizations that behind it Overview Properties Not technology focused Properties &amp;ndash; for each property expand on the work to support it, how to measure it, etc Efficiency: nudges, leaderboards, budgets, goals, etc QoS and cost post from a few years ago Reliability: incident program, metrics, Productivity: docs (search, structured), bootcamp, mentoring, build, test, deploy, avoiding approval gates (process impact, quality views help here!</description></item><item><title>Ten Years in the Valley: A collection of personal stories</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/ten-years-in-the-valley/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/ten-years-in-the-valley/</guid><description>Yeah, just like, a ton of personal stories from https://lethain.com/tags/stories</description></item><item><title>An Ethical Profession: An Unsubtitled Sequel to Elegant Puzzle</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/an-ethical-profession/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/an-ethical-profession/</guid><description>When folks asks if I’ll write another book after An Elegant Puzzle, I sometimes joke that if I wrote another management book it would be An Ethical Profession, and I could refer to them as AEP1 and AEP2. There are just so many management situations that push you to look at them through an ethical perspective.
A few of the situations that I’ve personally been in:
Senior technical leader ordering you to pull a candidate’s offer after they’d already given notice at their previous job due to an awkward conversation.</description></item><item><title>101 Ways to Increase Developer Productivity</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/101-ways-developer-productivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/books/101-ways-developer-productivity/</guid><description>Yeah, just like, 101 ways you could improve your and your team&amp;rsquo;s developer productivity. In a book.</description></item></channel></rss>