<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Exuberant Sketches</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Exuberant Sketches</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Will Larson</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:12:06 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing Better</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/writing-better/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 08:12:06 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/writing-better/</guid><description>I recently got a note from someone asking about writing, which is a topic I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write about before, some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve wrote on this topic:
Writing for Consumption (2008!)- mainly included because I wrote it in 2008 and it&amp;rsquo;s funny to read my old writing style How to be a tech influencer (2021) - my advice on how to do tech content distribution What I learned writing An Elegant Puzzle (2019?</description></item><item><title>Measuring Eng Impact</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/measuring-eng-impact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:52:09 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/measuring-eng-impact/</guid><description>This became Measures of engineering impact.
At today&amp;rsquo;s engineering leader breakfast (an extremely virtual breakfast, these days), we chatted about measuring engineering impact, which is quite different from measuring engineering velocity, even though velocity is a major input into impact.
Velocity metrics are the sort of things that you probably want to use to understand rather than to grade outcomes. Impact metrics should be things that you can grade against performance.</description></item><item><title>External stakeholders are hard</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/external-stakeholders/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 06:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/external-stakeholders/</guid><description>Yesterday I was chatting with someone when the eternal question to ex-Stripes came up, &amp;ldquo;When is Stripe going to IPO?&amp;rdquo; Personally, I haven&amp;rsquo;t the faintest clue, and from there the conversation moved towards Silicon Valley&amp;rsquo;s fascination with Stripe. Stripe does a lot of things well, and deserves credit for all of that, but I think the hardest thing that it does is often underappreciated: it manages to innovate quickly despite having a vast number of external stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Why and How I Write</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/why-write/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 18:03:14 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/why-write/</guid><description>One of the things I’ve enjoyed in the TechWriters forum has been folks talking about their writing process. A few folks mentioned the Fieldstone writing technique by Weinsberg. I’ve enjoyed Weinsberg’s other books, like “Being a technical leader” and “Secrets of a consultant”, so I decided to give it a read.
You can summarize the Fieldstone writing technique as: (1) collect related ideas in a file, (2) write stuff that energizes you, (3) switch projects to wherever you have the most energy.</description></item><item><title>Innovation</title><link>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/innovation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 19:16:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sketches.lethain.com/posts/innovation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Why can&amp;rsquo;t we do this in an hour?&amp;rdquo;
Velocity: experiments, explorations, investments
What are indicators
Small innovations Large innovations &amp;ndash; new fields, new products
What accelerates velocity
Developer workflows: check in, code review, test, deploy Stability: little time on failures, including reverts, etc Training Hiring Retention
What accelerates innovation?
Platforms Networks Users Brand Infrastructure
Misaligned incentives around resourcing/investment prevent innovation Innovator’s dilemma &amp;amp; solution It’s easy to innovate into high-margin products that draft on core biz Feature-teams can’t innovate Escaping the build trap Empowered Then let’s assume you do those, then Innovation comes from ?</description></item></channel></rss>